702.755.1041 (cell) jonathanmarx@gotohealthmedia.com

9209 Spruce Mountain Way Las Vegas, Nevada, 89134

LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/jonathanbmarx

# C-Level Executive with Focus in Medicine, Research and Health Communications

Results-oriented executive with repeat success in branding, launching, and growing products and services, in media and healthcare businesses. High-energy, enthusiastic, thinker for strategic positioning and business development. Ability to market and sell across multi-media platforms. Collaborative leader who has guided teams to surpass corporate goals through competition, market volatility, and transition. Have overseen budgets of \$100M and staff of 800. Have managed start-up teams in launches with early-round and bootstrap funding.

EXPERTISE	
<u>Pre-Launch</u>	Post-Launch
<ul> <li>Strategic Planning</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Social, Multi-Media, SEO Marketing</li> </ul>
<ul> <li>Financial Forecasting</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Sales</li> </ul>
<ul> <li>Business Development</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Team Building</li> </ul>
Brand Identification	<ul> <li>Change Management</li> </ul>

#### **EDUCATION**

Stanford University Graduate School of Business Masters in Business Administration (MBA)
Stanford University Bachelor of Arts in Psychology (BA)

## **AWARDS**

2022 Two Awards in Outstanding Health Education from Education 2.0 and BioPharma Europe.
 2013 Award for Online Commerce. 2012 APEX Award in Publishing Excellence.
 2011 A-CME Award for Best Innovation in Continuing Professional Development
 2004 Webby Award; 1995 Telly Award for TV Production; Cable Award for Community Relations;
 1992 Outstanding Corporate Leadership Award for AIDS Awareness

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# President and Founder GoToHealth Media, LLC

Apr '21 – Present

Las Vegas, NV

Founded hour-long video and podcast show featuring and promoting healthcare providers, non-profits and companies with byline "Elevate Your Life with Health News You Can Use" seen and downloaded 20,000+ times in 31 countries to date on <a href="https://gotohealthmedia.com">https://gotohealthmedia.com</a>, the largest internet radio station <a href="VoiceAmerica">VoiceAmerica</a>, and syndicated on seven podcast networks. Building professional client base with multi-media promotion, marketing, branding and networking services. Currently working on a client U.S. product launch of an innovative health wearable cleared by the FDA.

President Jan '10 – Dec '21

## **InQuill Medical Communications, LLC**

Santa Cruz, CA - Las Vegas, NV

Co-founded medical education company specializing in CME, multi-media content development, and multi-media marketing. Won 2013 award for online commerce, 2012 award for publishing, 2011 award for training. Purchased medical writing training company. Acquired large grants for national education projects. Expert at online marketing, promotion, social media, writing and adult learning. Multiple corporate and government contracts. 10-year trainer for the CDC in medical communications. Built and disseminated websites <a href="https://adhdinadults.com">https://adhdinadults.com</a> and <a href="https://achdinadults.com">https://achdinadults.com</a> and <a href="https://achdinadults.com">https://achdinadults.com</a> and <a href="https://achdevents.com">https://achdinadults.com</a> and <a href="https://achdevents.com">https://achdevents.com</a>. Closed business in 2021 to expand out of CME, start new venture and rebrand services.

Principal Jan '08 – Dec '09

## **Jonathan Marx Consulting**

Marin County, CA

Offered entrepreneurial and C-Level corporate expertise in consultation with start-ups in health services and products, and media. Focus on strategic planning, branding, and multi-media communications.

Jan '02 - Dec '07

#### Starfish Health Partners, LLC

Marin County, CA

Started and ran multi-media agency - marketing and promoting innovations in medicine and healthcare. Authored business plan and raised investor capital. Assembled team of consultants with expertise in branding, marketing, communications technologies, and professional medical education. Closed business in 2008 downturn.

- Created online professional community of 8,000 practitioners, clinics and institutions
- Produced / wrote health TV series and promotional campaign reaching 2 Million Bay Area homes
- Planned and executed 150 local, national and international live events and conferences on consumer health and professional medical education; attendees numbered from 50 to 700
- Created strategic relationships with corporate giants in tv, radio, publishing, and food retailing, as well as with large physician and practitioner groups
- Designed and produced world class websites and email marketing campaigns for new healthcare services
- Acquired accreditation to provide professional continuing medical and health education (CME,CEU)

President Feb 1999 – Jun 2001

**ISP Channel** (Division of Softnet, Inc)

San Francisco, Mountain View, CA

Scaled one of the first four high-speed cable modem ISP businesses in the country for nationwide high growth. Updated strategic direction based on market response and changing technology. Reworked revenue-split sales model, to achieve profit objectives. Managed overall operations. Guided Board to close business due to market consolidation and internet stock devaluation.

- Achieved 50 long-term contracts, 100-location marketing/engineering launches in the first year
- Brought \$60+ million expenditures in on budget, exceeding customer targets
- Negotiated and resolved \$80 million balance sheet with 20% lower cash flow than targeted, leaving investors \$70 million!

## **Vice President, Service Operations**

Jan 1998 – Jan 1999

TiVo, Inc.

Mountain View, CA

Recruited as first Vice President of Operations to support company during first-round funding launch.

- Created direct selling and service processes
- Developed projections and operations requirements for launch of service
- Provisioned customer management system, LD phone contracts, test environments

## Vice President, Strategy, Bus Dev

Oct 1996 - Dec 1997

# **Pacific Bell Yellow Pages**

San Francisco, CA

Recruited by President to evaluate and recommend new business opportunities for a \$1 billion advertising business with the largest sales force in California.

- Led ten Vice Presidents in development of strategy and vision process
- Spear-headed entry into Internet, direct mail, cable television, and specialty guides
- Identified \$100 Million (15%) revenue improvement opportunities in core business by highlighting actionable gaps in penetration and spending levels of advertisers
- Led fourteen Vice Presidents and their teams in creating merger benefits for \$2 billion business with Southwestern Bell Corporation; Recognized as best of 50 teams

Viacom Cable Jun 1982 – Jun 1996

# Senior Vice President, Jan - Jun 1996

Pleasanton, Livermore, San Francisco, CA

Managed staff and line operations with 800 employees for nine Northern California cable systems serving over 500,000 customers. Managed sales transition to TCI Cable in 1996.

# Vice President, Operations, Jan 1993 - Dec 1995

Managed 650 employees serving 400,000 customers through six General Managers, Regional Engineering, Commercial Sales, and Government Relations/Public Affairs. Negotiated deals with major broadcasters.

- Double sales among field staff by revising incentives/training/minimums
- Generated \$2M in new annual profit with standardization of pricing, customer service, and compensation among nine offices recently centralized.
- Hosted 36 episodes of "Cable Talk", monthly call-in talk show, winning 1993 BACE and 1994 Telly awards
- Defended the company against two lawsuits on late fees and obscenity, resulting in revised legislation

# Vice President, General Manager, Nov 1988 - Dec 1992

Directed 300 employees serving 158,000 customers in large urban cable system. Represented industry in television and radio interviews (CNN, KGO, San Francisco Chronicle). Negotiated union contracts.

- Grew customers 21%, revenue 49%, and pre-tax profit 70% over 4 years
- Launched first Pay-Per-View business now known as On-Demand
- Completed technical upgrade and marketed channel expansion
- Achieved de-certification of two union locals with improved employee relations

Assistant General Manager, Aug 1985 - Nov 1988 Regional Financial Manager, Jun 1982 – Aug 1985